## Summary

Software engineer with around a decade of experience building clean and maintainable software for a wide range of businesses ranging from Augmented Reality to Financial Services. Possess a strong technical background with a Masters Degree in Computer Engineering from the University of Florida. Lots of experience working in agile teams and also some independently as the only developer. Currently looking for a remote role with some challenging engineering work. I speak Spanish, Dutch, Hindi and Bengali as well:)

# App Showcase

Moneyou Go	iOS / Android
lacktriangledown Modern online mobile banking solution in NL and DE	March 2018 - December 2018
• 2dehands.be Largest Online Marketplace in Belgium	iOS June 2016 - December 2017
• Blippar Visual Object Recognition and Augmented Reality	iOS June 2015 - May 2016
• Layar World's first major Augmented Reality Platform	iOS November 2014 - May 2016
Jumbo  E-commerce app for Jumbo Supermarket	iOS February 2014 - November 2014

# Recent Work Experience

Rabobank (Financial Services)

Senior Mobile Engineer - Freelance

Utrecht, The Netherlands

March 2019 - May 2019

- Briefly joined the native mobile team at Rabobank and helped them with their hybrid app releases.
- Helped in interviewing new iOS Candidates
- Contributed to discussions about Banking IT architecture

 $Moneyou \; / \; ABN \; AMRO \; (\texttt{Financial Services})$ 

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

March 2018 - December 2018

- Senior Mobile Engineer Freelance
  - Interview new iOS Candidates
  - Won moneyou hackathon and successfully implemented suggested features in the app

- Part of mobile team doing iOS and Android feature development and releases

- Part of team creating a new and compliant banking backend infrastructure with AWS Serverless Lambdas
- Markplaats / Ebay Inc. (Classifieds)

Senior iOS Engineer - Freelance

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

June 2016 - December 2017

- Singlehandedly maintain the 2dehands.be App for Belgium serving millions of users
- Part of the ebay global mobile team building classified apps for 11 different countries for example Gumtree UK
- Setup all required processes such as Automated Testing, Continuous Integration, Crash Analysis etc.
- Successfully hired and trained replacement for the role before exit

# **Previous Work Experience**

Layar / Blippar (Augmented Reality)

Amsterdam, The Netherlands November 2014 - May 2016

Senior iOS Engineer

- Lead Developer for the iOS Layar App that makes millions of users see Augmented Reality
- Lead Developer for the iOS Layar SDK that help businesses make Augmented Reality solutions
- Part of the team building the Blippar App for visual search

# IceMobile Agency Senior iOS Engineer

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

February 2014 - November 2014

- Senior developer in the iOS development team building apps for the leading supermarkets in the Netherlands such as Jumbo and Albert Heijn
- Gathering business requirements and coming up with efficient technical solutions to address them
- Automating user interface testing and setting up continuous integration

Ebuddy

iOS Developer

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

June 2013 - January 2014

- Working in the iOS development team building the messaging app XMS that had millions of users around the world and was a competitor to watsapp

# MicroStrategy Inc.

McLean,VA

Software Engineer

September 2010 - January 2012

- Worked on several iOS development projects for the clients of Microstrategy and helped automate various tasks. Also helped develop the microstrategy SDK. iOS was a pretty new technology at this point so this was some really good experience.

# Citisync.com

Gainesville.FL

iOS Developer

January 2010- July 2010

Singlehandedly built the citisync iOS Application. This was when iOS 3 was the latest version. Also
my first experience as an iOS Developer and it piqued my interest in the field

#### Bloomberg LP

New York, NY

Financial Software Development Intern

May 2009 - August 2009

- As an intern in the manhattan office, I helped out with a number of projects in the Global Trading team writing code in C++ and managing large mainframe supercomputers

## Education

## University of Florida

Gainesville,FL

Masters in Computer Engineering

August 2008 - August 2010

- CGPA: 3.6/4.0

## Skills

Languages: Swift, Objective C, C, C++, Python, Bash, Javascript, Java, Kotlin

**Technical Skills:** iOS, Android, TDD, Automated Testing, CI, fastlane, git, xcode, Security, Machine Learning, Restful API Design, AWS Serverless, Agile/Scrum, Estimation, Writing User Stories, Presentations

## Other Interests

Pilot Training, Salsa Dancing, Travel, Pool and Snooker